Preliminary Inventory of the Council for a Community of Democracies records
Hoover Institution Archives
Council for a Community of Democracies records
1993-2015
2016C27
Hoover Institution Archives
37 manuscript boxes (15.4 linear feet)
Minutes, correspondence, conference materials, memoranda, reports, financial and fundraising records, and printed matter relating to the Community of Democracies. Includes records of the Next Century Initiative.
Council for a Community of Democracies.
Access
The collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2016.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note
Private nonprofit American organization to promote international democracy; secretariat for the international Community of Democracies; successor to Committee for a Community of Democracies--USA and Next Century Initiative.
Scope and Contents of Collection
Minutes, correspondence, conference materials, memoranda, reports, financial and fundraising records, and printed matter relating to the Community of Democracies. Includes records of the Next Century Initiative.
Democracy.; International organization.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Relations.
- International Advisory Committee (Box 1)
- Seoul Ministerial, 2002
- Santiago Ministerial, 2005
- Bamako Ministerial, 2007 (Boxes 1-2)
- Africa and democracy (Box 2)
- Southern Sudan conference
- Cameroon Free Press in Africa conference, Douala, 2005
- Togo
- Bridge from the Americas to Africa (OAS/AU)
- European Support for Democracy
- United Nations Democracy caucus (Box 3)
- UNDP (United Nations Development Program)
- United Nations Democracy Fund
- Wilson Center conference
- ISC (International Steering Committee)
- Bucharest CO/NGO regional conference (Box 4)
- World Movement for Democracy (WMD) Durban workshop
- Community of Democracies Ministerial Lisbon
- Brussels roundtable
- American University course and conference
- Warsaw Democracy Education Working Group, 2012
- Ulaanbaatar Roundtable on Democracy in Asia
- Vilnius (Lithuania Chairmanship of Community of Democracies) (Box 5)
- Kiev World Movement for Democracy Conference, 2008
- New Delhi Roundtable
- Brussels Roundtable, 2009
- Parliamentary Forum
- Taiwan Roundtable
- UC Berkeley conference
- Pretoria conference, 2010
- Community of Democracies Working Group on Democracy and Development
- Lima World Movement for Democracy conference, 2012 (Box 6)
- Community of Democracies Budapest
- Amman Roundtable
- Palmer Prize
- Military engagement handbook
- ICDT (International Center for Democratic Transition)
- Diplomat's handbook (Box 7)
- Democracy Education
- DOHA: Toward an Arab Democratic Charter (Box 8)
- Tunisia Democracy Education Pilot Project (Box 9)
- Ghana Workshop on Democracy Education (Box 10)
- Kosovo Workshop on Democracy Education
- Military and Democratic Transition
- Advisory Council (Boxes 10-11)
- US (Council for a Community of Democracies) Coordinating Committee (Box 11)
- Walt Raymond correspondence
- Council for a Community of Democracies/Community of Democracies OAS Regional Conference
- European Union (EU)/Community of Democracies (Box 12)
- Community of Democracies Convening Group
- Council for a Community of Democracies Associates
- Published Council for a Community of Democracies reports, brochures, and books (Boxes 12-15)
- Vision papers (Box 15)
- Council for a Community of Democracies Task Forces
- Letters to presidential candidates and other policy makers (Box 16)
- Council for a Community of Democracies Board meetings, 2001-2015 (Boxes 16-18)
- Council for a Community of Democracies organization and board members (Boxes 19-21)
- Charlottesville conference (Box 21)
- US candidates endorsement requests
- Dreir/Lantos bill
- Democracy Dialogues
- "A Community of Democracies Handbook"
- American University course
- Bahrain
- Istanbul, 2006 (Box 22)
- Bellagio
- Cameroon trip: African Press Federation project
- Convening 10 (Convening Group of the Council of the Community of Democracies)
- European Network Project, 2003 (Boxes 22-24)
- Website press and mailing lists (Boxes 24-25)
- International Parliamentary program (Box 25)
- International Network of Parliaments
- ACILS
- Canadian Donner Foundation
- Denmark, France, U.K. (Boxes 25-26)
- IDEA International elections (Box 26)
- United Nations
- UNA-USA
- Streit Council
- Westminster Foundation
- Wilson Center for Scholars
- World Movement for Democracy (WMD)
- Fundraising campaign and development (Boxes 27-30)
- Contributions (Boxes 30-33)
- U.S. Coordination Committee (NGO/Council for a Community of Democracies) (Box 33)
- UN Democracy Caucus
- Community of Democracies Convening Group and Council for a Community of Democracies NGO role
- Standards for Community of Democracies membership (Box 34)
- Parliaments in Community of Democracies (Canadian Project) (Box 35)
- New Century Initiatives, Inc.
- IABA meeting in Singapore
- New Century Initiatives
- Council for a Community of Democracies incorporation
- Council for a Community of Democracies and US National Committee, UNESCO
- Council for a Community of Democracies Board meetings, 2003-2006
- Council for a Community of Democracies audit (Box 36)
- United Nations Democracy group
- Community of Democracies Convening groups - Ukraine
- Fund proposal
- Mark Palmer book
- North American Regional workshop
- Presidential candidate letter
- ICDT origins
- Board member (Box 37)
- Board member Hamilton
- Global group/International Steering Committee
- Board member
- "Great Decisions" proposal
- Proposals to US government
- Bennington College project
- Board member Borden's proposals